<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.1.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-12-01T11:36:10-06:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Dani Jota</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Nomad review: Lisbon</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/lifestyle/2019/02/05/nomad-review-lisbon.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Nomad review: Lisbon" /><published>2019-02-05T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2019-02-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/lifestyle/2019/02/05/nomad-review-lisbon</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/lifestyle/2019/02/05/nomad-review-lisbon.html">&lt;p&gt;As you may know so far, I’ve been working from Lisbon for a few weeks on last January and this is my nomad review of the city. So if you are considering work from there, keep reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve stayed near Anjos metro station (about 10 minutes to the center) and working from Startup Lisbon, which is an incubator and also has a coworking space in the f*** center of Lisbon. Was awesome to work from there.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dani</name></author><category term="lifestyle" /><summary type="html">As you may know so far, I’ve been working from Lisbon for a few weeks on last January and this is my nomad review of the city. So if you are considering work from there, keep reading.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2019 here we go!</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/lifestyle/2019/01/15/here-we-go.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2019 here we go!" /><published>2019-01-15T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2019-01-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/lifestyle/2019/01/15/here-we-go</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/lifestyle/2019/01/15/here-we-go.html">&lt;p&gt;2018 has been an amazing year. Full of trips, adventures, new emotions and surprising experiences. I’ve met great new people and other has left. Personally, I’ve lived a lot of new experiences with Waynabox and I’ve visited places where I’d stay forever.
It would take a full new post if I wanted to review my past 2018 actually, but I write down this for another reason. 2019 is already here and that’s a fact. I’m not a person who writes down his new year resolutions but this year it’s going to be different and I’m gonna try it (well, we are already at mid January). So here is my 2019 resolutions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Write more post about UX research&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every time I like more and more to analyze and explore the field of UX. How the digital user (or not) interacts with the technology and the world around us. I think it’s a super important aspect in our lives and many times we don’t even stop to think about it. Actually, the field of UX is a very unscientific field, where, at best, A/B testing studies are done to assess whether a proposed solution is better than another to solve a problem based on a behavior made by a number of people but I think there is still much to improve and demonstrate. That’s why this year I’d like to improve Waynabox UX, analyze the changes and publish them here to bring the community a little more knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Travel more&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don’t think it makes this point. Lately, I have traveled a lot in Europe and this year I would like to discover cities and countries outside the continent to see clearer contrasts of culture, gastronomy and traditions. If all goes well, I will achieve it next month traveling to the U.S. and Mexico to work from there (here you have more info of what I’m talking about)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Build something for travelers&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With each technology that appears, the new flight search engine that is born and new travel APIs a set of tools are generated being able to create new products for people who like to travel in a different way. That’s why this year I want to take advantage of those resources to build something that helps people who spend their lives traveling more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get in shape&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since some year ago I’ve been thinking about getting in shape (in the end, my daily activity until today is reduced to going from home to work, sitting for 8 hours and going from work to home) and I have always postponed (trying to justify it with some absurd excuse). Last November I started to run (I even did 60km a week) and I started to lose weight until a knee injury interrupted my workouts. Now that I’m recovered I’m ready to start running again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s all! I think are all reasonable and hopefully, I’ll achieve all of them.
I’ll be posting my progress around here, so stay tuned.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dani</name></author><category term="lifestyle" /><summary type="html">2018 has been an amazing year. Full of trips, adventures, new emotions and surprising experiences. I’ve met great new people and other has left. Personally, I’ve lived a lot of new experiences with Waynabox and I’ve visited places where I’d stay forever. It would take a full new post if I wanted to review my past 2018 actually, but I write down this for another reason. 2019 is already here and that’s a fact. I’m not a person who writes down his new year resolutions but this year it’s going to be different and I’m gonna try it (well, we are already at mid January). So here is my 2019 resolutions:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">I’ve turned 27 and I’m starting a digital nomad life</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/nomad/life/2018/11/24/im-starting-a-digital-nomad-life.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="I’ve turned 27 and I’m starting a digital nomad life" /><published>2018-11-24T10:32:53-06:00</published><updated>2018-11-24T10:32:53-06:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/nomad/life/2018/11/24/im-starting-a-digital-nomad-life</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/nomad/life/2018/11/24/im-starting-a-digital-nomad-life.html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;how-did-i-came-here&quot;&gt;How did I came here?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4 years ago I started to dedicate my life, with 2 friends, to build one I idea we had once: make people travel in a different way across Europe. This is how Waynabox started. These 4 years have been awesome; full of emotions, knowing new people and learning more than an after-university grade could teach me, but I’ve been too focused on doing everything works smoothly that I’ve not had time to do what I enjoy the most: &lt;strong&gt;travel&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Travel is one of the best things you can do in life. They say travel is the only thing you buy that makes you richer. And it’s true. You are buying an experience and, as human behavior is defined by experiences, after all, it defines who you are. There is nothing like seeing other cultures, know how do the people live in the other part of the globe, discover traditions that never could imagine o connect with someone at a glance that you have never seen before. Travel changes your perception about what you have, who you are and what do you want.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/croatia1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Myself visiting Split, one of the most beautiful cities in Croatia&quot; title=&quot;Myself visiting Split, one of the most beautiful cities in Croatia&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Myself visiting Split, one of the most beautiful cities in Croatia&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last November 16 I turned 27, and with the 30s crisis approaching (yeah, you now will say I’m still young and so on) you start asking yourself some things. What I just did achieve? Did I miss something? How much time I have before I take a house loan?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I think it’s a good moment to stop and think about what is what I want and which things are those ones which make me happy. And one of them is travel. Is true I’ve traveled a lot lastly through Europe, but I’ve never known what does it feels like being on vacations more than 2 days in a row and disconnect from your work entirely, something I suppose it’s important to do from time to time. Knowing that Waynabox is still running good -and hopefully it will do in the near future, I think a good solution is to work traveling. Good to me, being developer allows you to work from anywhere where you have internet and coffee to convert into code, so I started to interest in this style of life, and I saw there are a lot of freelancers/developers that do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to left the flat where I live, sell my motorbike and start a digital nomad life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know it’s not a lifestyle for everyone, but now I’m not chained to any loan and still single, is a good time to give it a try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To not be disconnected entirely from my work team, I’ve decided to do travel cycles, like 2-3 months traveling and one in my birthplace (Barcelona) to don’t lose the contact with my family and friends. This way I’ll still be able to discover the world without and keep time for being with the people I love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;where-do-i-start-from&quot;&gt;Where do I start from?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The same way you usually do an MVP when you are trying to launch an idea, I’m making a pilot journey to Lisbon, where I’ll be working from 2 weeks to establish some protocols, try remote working tools and adapt myself to this new lifestyle. Why Lisbon? Well, is one of my favorite city in Europe. The food is amazing, it’s cheap and I have some friends there. There is no better way to start this adventure!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The nice thing about being a digital nomad is that you are free to go wherever you want and decide where are you going to live your life in your next months it’s not easy. Nomadlist helped me a lot to decide but I’ve always wanted to visit two regions: South America and Asia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As recently new low-cost airlines appeared to do long-haul trips, the price tickets for going to America are really cheap now, so I’ve decided to start from visiting Mexico (I like spicy food and my surname is Mendoza, you know) and also visit some other US cities in the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/posts/route.png&quot; alt=&quot;How my route looks like so far&quot; title=&quot;How my route looks like so far&quot; class=&quot;img-responsive&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;em&gt;How my route looks like so far&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For all of those who are thinking about taking this lifestyle or just want to know about how my adventure is going I’ve opened this blog (I hope I can keep updated, I’m not really used to write too much about my life) where I’ll be posting my trips, pictures, experiences, and tips about the places I visit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is all for now. I’m really excited about to start this adventure. I’m conscious I’ll know a lot of new people, I’ll discover new cultures and I’ll life new unique experiences. But life is about that. Isn’t it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keep talking&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Dani</name></author><category term="nomad" /><category term="life" /><summary type="html">How did I came here? 4 years ago I started to dedicate my life, with 2 friends, to build one I idea we had once: make people travel in a different way across Europe. This is how Waynabox started. These 4 years have been awesome; full of emotions, knowing new people and learning more than an after-university grade could teach me, but I’ve been too focused on doing everything works smoothly that I’ve not had time to do what I enjoy the most: travel.</summary></entry></feed>